A Guide to the JDR 3rd Fund records FA081
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Youth Task Force - General Correspondence, 1969-1974; 01; 19 Cubic Feet 38 document cases
  - San Francisco Dialogs - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 268)
  - San Francisco Dialogs - Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 269)
  - San Francisco - Organizations, 1969-1973 (Box 27, Folder 270)
  - San Francisco - Organizations, 1969-1973 (Box 27, Folder 271)
  - Sanctuary, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 272)
  - Scholarship, Education and Defense Fund for Racial Equality, Inc. (SEDFRE), 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 273)
  - Shuman, James, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 274)
  - Source, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 275)
  - Stanford Research Institute, 1967-1971 (Box 27, Folder 276)
  - Stern Fund, 1969-1973 (Box 28, Folder 277)
  - Stone Foundation, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 278)
  - Student Advisory Committee on International Affairs - Project Dialogue, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 279)
  - Student American Medical Association - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 280)
  - Student American Medical Association - Publications, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 281)
  - Student Community Housing Corporation, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 282)
  - Student Information Center, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 283)
  - Student National Education Association, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 284)
  - Student Rights Project, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 285)
  - Student Vote, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 286)
  - Subscriptions, 1971-1974 (Box 29, Folder 287)
  - Miscellaneous (T) (Box 29, Folder 288)
  - Texas Intercollegiate Student Association, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 289)
  - Texas Intercollegiate Student Association, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 290)
  - Texas Legal Defense Fund - Packet, 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 291)
  - Tie Line - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 292)
  - Tie Line - Publications, 1970-1973 (Box 30, Folder 293)
  - Time, Inc., 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 294)
  - "Times", New York, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 295)
  - TRW, Inc., 1971 (Box 30, Folder 296)
  - Tulsa Chamber of Commerce, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 297)
  - Tutorial Assistance Center, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 298)
  - Twin Cities Dialog (Minneapolis), 1970-1973 (Box 30, Folder 299)
  - Miscellaneous (U) (Box 30, Folder 300)
  - United Nations Conference on Human Development, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 301)
  - United States Coalition for Development, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 302)
  - United States Youth Council, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 303)
  - University for Young Americans, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 304)
  - Up with People, Inc., 1971 (Box 31, Folder 305)
  - Urban Corps, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 306)
  - Miscellaneous (V) (Box 31, Folder 307)
  - Vacations, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 308)
  - Vietnam Era Veterans, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 309)
  - Vollertson, Rick, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 310)
  - Miscellaneous (W) (Box 31, Folder 311)
  - Walks for Development, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 312)
  - Washington Research Project, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 313)
  - Washington Workshops, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 314)
  - Westbrook, Joseph A., 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 315)
  - Westchester County Dialog, 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 316)
  - Westchester Showcase, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 317)
  - Western Reserve Education Fund, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 318)
  - West Side Development Corporation, Cleveland, Ohio, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 319)
  - White House Conference on Youth, 1971 - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 320)
  - White House Conference on Youth, 1971 - Background Materials (Box 32, Folder 321)
  - White House Conference on Youth, 1971 - Background Materials (Box 32, Folder 322)
  - White House Conference on Youth, 1971 - Background Materials (Box 32, Folder 323)
  - White House Youth Office, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 324)
  - Whitney Foundation, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 325)
  - Women Involved, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 326)
  - Women's Projects, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 327)
  - Women's Projects, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 328)
  - Miscellaneous (X-Z) (Box 33, Folder 329)
  - Young Democrats, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 330)
  - Youth Development and Delinquency Prevention, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 331)
  - Young Presidents' Organization, Chicago Chapter, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 332)
  - Young Workers, 1972-1974 (Box 33, Folder 333)
  - Youth - General Information, 1969-1972 (Box 34, Folder 334)
  - Youth Business, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 335)
  - Youth Citizenship, Inc., 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 336)
  - Youth Citizenship, Inc., 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 337)
  - Youth Liberation, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 338)
  - Youth Marketing Firms, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 339)
  - Youth Organizations United, 1968-1971 (Box 35, Folder 340)
  - Youth Programs Act of 1972 (Box 35, Folder 341)
  - Youth Project, 1970-1972 (Box 35, Folder 342)
  - Youth Research, 1970-1972 (Box 35, Folder 343)
  - Youth Research Center, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 344)
  - Youth Task Force - Description, 1970-1974 (Box 35, Folder 345)
  - Youth Task Force - Papers and Proceedings, 1970-1974 (Box 36, Folder 346)
  - Youth Task Force - Papers and Proceedings, 1970-1974 (Box 36, Folder 347)
  - Youth Task Force - Papers and Proceedings, 1970-1974 (Box 36, Folder 348)
  - Youth Task Force - Papers and Proceedings, 1970-1974 (Box 36, Folder 349)
  - Youth Task Force - Papers and Proceedings, 1970-1974 (Box 36, Folder 350)
  - Youth to Youth, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 351)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (A-Ca) (Box 36, Folder 352)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Ce-Cl) (Box 37, Folder 353)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Cl-Col) (Box 37, Folder 354)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Com-Ez) (Box 37, Folder 355)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (F-Ha) (Box 37, Folder 356)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Human Development Foundation) (Box 37, Folder 357)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (I-L) (Box 37, Folder 358)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (M-O) (Box 38, Folder 359)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (P) (Box 38, Folder 360)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (T-To) (Box 38, Folder 360A)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Tr-Wz) (Box 38, Folder 360B)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (X-Z) (Box 38, Folder 360C)
  - Award for "Youth's Agenda for the Seventies", 1973 (Box OS 1, Folder 1)
  - Black P. Stone Nation - Newspapers, c. 1971-1972; See also Box 3, Folder 39 (Box OS 1, Folder 2)
  - Tie-Line - Publications - Computer Printout, 1971; See also Box 30, Folder 293 (Box OS 1, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam Era Veterans - Interview Schedule, n.d.; See also Box 31, Folder 309 (Box OS 1, Folder 4)
  - Youth Citizenship Fund, Inc. - 1971 Report, See also Box 34, Folder 336-337 (Box OS 1, Folder 5)
- Youth Task Force - Publications, 1970-1975; 02; 0.5 Cubic Feet 2 document cases
  This series contains an administrative file and correspondence about publications of the Youth Task Force, especially "Youth's Agenda for the Seventies" (1971). Also included is a draft of "The Second American Revolution" by John D. Rockefeller 3rd and a selection of his speeches on youth concerns.
  - Administrative File, 1970-1976 (Box 39, Folder 361)
  - Gerzon, Mark, 1971-1973 (Box 39, Folder 362)
  - Guettinger Fundraising Manual, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 363)
  - Youth/Establishment Dialogs, 1972-1975 (Box 39, Folder 364)
  - "Youth's Agenda for the Seventies" - Summary Report on White House Conference on Youth, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 365)
  - "Youth's Agenda for the Seventies" - Distribution, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 366)
  - "Youth's Agenda for the Seventies" - Publication, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 367)
  - "Youth's Agenda for the Seventies" - Promotion and Publicity, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 368)
  - Rockefeller, John D. 3rd - Book Draft - "Wide Open for Change" (Published as "The Second American Revolution") (Box 40, Folder 369)
  - Speeches, 1968-1971 (Box 40, Folder 370)
  - Speeches, 1968-1971 (Box 40, Folder 371)
- Youth Task Force - Yankelovich Studies, 1970-1976; 03; 11 Cubic Feet 12 document cases
  This series contains general correspondence, copies of drafts and final copies of the various studies conducted by Daniel Yankelovich, Inc. for the Youth Task Force (1971-1974), promotion and distribution records, computer tables, and keypunch cards.
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 1a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 1b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 2a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 2b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 3a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 3b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 4a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 4b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 5a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 5b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 6a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 6b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 7a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public Data (Box 7b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public/College Data (Box 8a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - General Public/College Data (Box 8b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - College Data (Box 9a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - College Data (Box 9b, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - College Data (Box 10a, Folder 1)
  - Computer Keypunch Cards for 1973 Survey - College Data (Box 10b, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 372)
  - General Correspondence - Heath, Ronald, 1974-1975 (Box 41, Folder 373)
  - General Distribution Lists, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 374)
  - General Distribution Lists, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 375)
  - Special Requests, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 376)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Copy of Publication, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 377)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Publication Correspondence, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 378)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Promotion and Publicity, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 379)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Distribution, 1970-1975 (Box 41, Folder 380)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests from Schools and Colleges, 1971-1972 (Box 41, Folder 381)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests from Schools and Colleges, 1972-1976 (Box 42, Folder 382)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (A-B), 1971 (Box 42, Folder 383)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (C), 1971 (Box 42, Folder 384)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (D-E), 1971 (Box 42, Folder 385)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (F-G), 1971 (Box 43, Folder 386)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (H-I), 1971 (Box 43, Folder 387)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (J-L), 1971 (Box 43, Folder 388)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (M), 1971 (Box 43, Folder 389)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (N), 1971 (Box 43, Folder 390)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (O-P), 1971 (Box 44, Folder 391)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (Q-R), 1971 (Box 44, Folder 392)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (S), 1971 (Box 44, Folder 393)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (T-V), 1971 (Box 44, Folder 394)
  - Youth and the Establishment - Requests for Copies (W-Z), 1971 (Box 44, Folder 395)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Copy of Publication, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 396)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Manuscript Draft (Entitled "Values and Politics on Campus") (Box 45, Folder 397)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Manuscript Mastercopy (Box 45, Folder 398)
  - Changing Values on Campus - College Youth Survey, 1970-1971 (Box 45, Folder 399)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Commentary by Mark Gerzon and William Eberle, 1970-1971 (Box 46, Folder 400)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Pre-Publication Copies - Distribution (Box 46, Folder 401)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Publication, 1971-1972 (Box 46, Folder 402)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Promotion and Publicity, 1972-1973 (Box 46, Folder 403)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Promotion and Publicity, 1972-1973 (Box 46, Folder 404)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Copyright Royalties, 1972-1973 (Box 46, Folder 405)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Requests for Copies (A-Z) (Box 46, Folder 406)
  - Changing Values on Campus - Acknowledgements of Copies (A-Z) (Box 46, Folder 407)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Copy of Publication, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 408)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Draft Chapters, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 409)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Draft, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 410)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Revised Draft, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 411)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Draft (Part 1), 1973 (Box 47, Folder 412)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Draft (Part 2), 1973 (Box 48, Folder 413)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Advanced Draft, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 414)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Final Draft, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 415)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - The 1973 Study of American Youth (Box 48, Folder 416)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Summary Report, 1973 (Box 49, Folder 417)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Computer Tables, Volume A, 1973 (Box 49, Folder 418)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Computer Tables, Volume B, 1973 (Box 49, Folder 419)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Computer Tables, Volume C, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 420)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Computer Tables, Volume D, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 421)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Computer Tables, Volume E, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 422)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Draft Copies, 1974 (Box 50, Folder 423)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Galley Sheets (Entitled "A New Morality"), 1973 (Box 50, Folder 424)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Questionnaire, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 425)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Questionnaire and Survey Material, 1973 (Box 50, Folder 426)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Administration, 1971-1976 (Box 51, Folder 427)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Foundation Support, 1972-1974 (Box 51, Folder 428)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Foundation Support, 1972-1974 (Box 51, Folder 429)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Computer Records, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 430)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Publication, 1972-1974 (Box 51, Folder 431)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Promotion and Publicity, 1973-1974 (Box 51, Folder 432)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Promotion and Publicity - Press Conference, May 21, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 433)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Press Coverage, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 434)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Distribution, 1974-1975 (Box 51, Folder 435)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - Reaction and Requests to Quote, 1974-1975 (Box 51, Folder 436)
  - Changing Youth Values in the Seventies - "Generations Apart: A Study of the Generation Gap, 1969" (Study by Yankelovich Conducted for CBS News), 1973 (Box 51, Folder 437)
  - Graphs and Summaries of Youth Attitudes (Box 51A, Folder 437A)
  - Graphs and Summaries of Youth Attitudes (Box 51A, Folder 437A)
- Philanthropy, 1969-1972; 04; 0.5 Cubic Feet 1 document case
  This series is an alphabetical file consisting of proposals, correspondence, grant files, and reports on philanthropic activity and corporate responsibility in American life.
  - Alcor, Inc. - Proposal, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 438)
  - Corporate Responsibility, 1969-1970 (Box 52, Folder 439)
  - Corporate Responsibility, 1969-1970 (Box 52, Folder 440)
  - Effects of Philanthropy on Education in Cleveland, Ohio, 1969 (Box 52, Folder 441)
  - Harvard Project, 1971-1972 (Box 52, Folder 442)
    Grant #71114-S
  - Stanford University, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 443)
    Grant #EC-7198-S
- Bicentennial Project, 1971-1976; 05; 1.5 Cubic Feet 2 document cases
  This series contains surveys, reports, correspondence, and grant files relating to the activities of the Fund in coordinating efforts to encourage the participation of the private sector in this national celebration.
  - Washington Survey, 1971-1975 (Box 53, Folder 444)
  - Washington Survey, 1971-1975 (Box 53, Folder 445)
  - USA 200 - Ruder and Finn, 1974-1975 (Box 53, Folder 446)
  - National Committee for the Bicentennial Era, 1974-1976 (Box 53, Folder 447)
  - National Committee for the Bicentennial Era, 1974-1976 (Box 53, Folder 448)
  - National Committee for the Bicentennial Era - Barrett, Richard W., 1973-1974 (Box 53, Folder 449)
  - Report on the Bicentennial Commissions of the States and Territories - Roger J. Guettinger, 1973-1974 (Box 54, Folder 450)
  - Afro-American Bicentennial Corporation, 1973-1977 (Box 54, Folder 451)
  - The Bicentennial Council of the Thirteen Original States, 1973-1975 (Box 54, Folder 452)
    Grant #EC-74114-B
  - Citizen Involvement Network, 1974-1975 (Box 54, Folder 453)
    Grant #EC-74115-B, EC-7576-B
  - Citizen Involvement Network, 1974-1975 (Box 54, Folder 454)
  - Federalism Seventy-Six, 1973-1974 (Box 54, Folder 455)
    Grant #B-7388-S
  - The Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 456)
- Other Projects, 1965-1976; 06; 1.5 Cubic Feet 3 document cases
  This series is an alphabetical file consisting of correspondence, reports, grant material, and reference files relating to projects not covered by the Fund's three major programs. Topics include housing and the Indonesian Volunteer Service.
  - American Association of Fund-Raising Council, 1969-1972 (Box 55, Folder 457)
  - American Association of Junior Colleges, 1969-1970 (Box 55, Folder 458)
    Grant #B-7070-S
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1964-1971 (Box 55, Folder 459)
    Grant #B-6891-S
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1964-1971 (Box 55, Folder 460)
  - Council on Language Teaching Development, 1967-1968 (Box 55, Folder 461)
  - English Language Drama, 1968-1976 (Box 55, Folder 462)
    Grant #B-69102-S
  - Foundation Center Grant, 1967-1975 (Box 55, Folder 463)
    Grant #B-69103-S
  - Harvard - George C. Lodge, 1968-1969 (Box 56, Folder 464)
  - Housing, 1972 (Box 56, Folder 465)
  - Housing, 1972 (Box 56, Folder 466)
  - Housing - Reference Material, 1968-1973 (Box 56, Folder 467)
  - Indonesian Volunteer Service, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 468)
  - International House of Japan, 1967-1971 (Box 56, Folder 469)
    Grant #B-6994-S
  - International Secretariat for Volunteer Service, 1967-1971 (Box 56, Folder 470)
    Grant #B-6889-S, B-6890-S
  - International Secretariat for Volunteer Service - Publications, 1968-1969 (Box 57, Folder 471)
  - McLean, E. Lee, 1967-1969 (Box 57, Folder 472)
  - National Information Bureau - D. Paul Reed, 1969 (Box 57, Folder 473)
  - Japan Broadcasting Corporation (NHK), 1969-1970 (Box 57, Folder 474)
    Grant #B-6993-S
  - Press Foundation of India, 1967-1972 (Box 57, Folder 475)
    Grant #EC-6859-S
  - Talbot, Phillips, 1968-1969 (Box 57, Folder 476)
    Grant #B-6978-S
  - University of Tokyo Press, 1967-1968 (Box 57, Folder 477)
  - Videotape Project - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC), 1969 (Box 57, Folder 478)
    Grant #B-69101-S
  - Declinations, 1966-1970 (Box 57, Folder 479)
- "The JDR 3rd Fund and Asia, 1963-1975", 1963-1978; 07; 3.5 Cubic Feet 7 document cases
  This series consists of correspondence, drafts, questionnaire responses, distribution records relating to this report, together with notes and drafts by Elaine Moss and Cristy West, who were instrumental in its preparation. Also included in this series are two boxes consisting of an index to the project activities of the Asian Cultural Program, prepared for use in this report.
  - Copy of Report (Box 58, Folder 480)
  - Manuscript of Text (Box 58, Folder 481)
  - Mas/Lucas Trip, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 482)
  - Questionnaire to Grantees - Cover Letters and Responses, 1975-1978 (Box 58, Folder 483)
  - Statistical Data (Box 58, Folder 484)
  - Photos Submitted (Box 58, Folder 485)
    Xerox copies only.
  - Supporting Text for Photos, 1977-1978 (Box 58, Folder 486)
  - Expenses, 1977-1978 (Box 59, Folder 487)
  - Press Releases and Cover Letters, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 488)
  - Cover Letters to Rockefeller Family Members - Porter McKeever, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 489)
  - Acknowledgements, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 490)
  - Requests, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 491)
  - Distribution Summary (Box 59, Folder 492)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 59, Folder 493)
  - Questionnaire Responses - Asia (Box 59, Folder 494)
  - Questionnaire Responses - China (Box 60, Folder 495)
  - Questionnaire Responses - India (Box 60, Folder 496)
  - Questionnaire Responses - Indonesia (Box 60, Folder 497)
  - Questionnaire Responses - Japan (Box 60, Folder 498)
  - Questionnaire Responses - Korea (Box 60, Folder 499)
  - Questionnaire Responses - Philippines (Box 60, Folder 500)
  - Questionnaire Responses - Thailand (Box 60, Folder 501)
  - Questionnaire Responses - Miscellaneous (Box 60, Folder 502)
  - Fellowship, Research, and Travel Grants, 1963-1975 (Box 60, Folder 503)
  - Project Grants, 1963-1975 (Box 60, Folder 504)
  - Grant Recipients by Country, 1963-1975 (Box 60, Folder 505)
  - Preliminary Data (Box 60A, Folder A)
  - Elaine Moss Material - Notes, 1977 (Box 60A, Folder B)
  - Elaine Moss Material - Drafts, 1977 (Box 60A, Folder C)
  - Elaine Moss Material - Grant Listings (Box 60B, Folder D)
  - Cristy West Material - Notes from Questionnaires, 1976 (Box 60B, Folder E)
  - Cristy West Material - Notes from Interviews, 1976 (Box 60B, Folder F)
  - Cristy West Material - Drafts, 1976 (Box 60B, Folder G)
  - Project and Fellowship Cards (A-K) (Box 60C)
  - Project and Fellowship Cards (L-Z) (Box 60D)
  - "The JDR 3rd Fund and Asia, 1963-1975" - Grantee Distribution Lists (Box OS 1)
  - "The JDR 3rd Fund and Asia, 1963-1975" - Charts (Box OS 1)
  - "The JDR 3rd Fund and Asia, 1963-1975" - Galley Sheets (Box OS 1)
- English Language Teaching in Japan, 1956-1974; 08; 1.5 Cubic Feet 4 document cases
  Series 8 contains correspondence, reports, manuals, and grant files relating to the Fund's support of the English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) and the Committee for Cooperation on English in Japan (CCCJ).
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) - Correspondence with W. Freeman Twaddell, 1956-1960 (Box 61, Folder 506)
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) - Correspondence with W. Freeman Twaddell, 1956-1960 (Box 61, Folder 507)
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) - Correspondence with W. Freeman Twaddell, 1956-1960 (Box 61, Folder 508)
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) - Correspondence with W. Freeman Twaddell, 1956-1960 (Box 61, Folder 509)
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) - 1st Year Instructional Manual (Box 61, Folder 510)
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) - 1st Year Instructional Manual (Box 61, Folder 511)
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC), 1961-1962 (Box 62, Folder 512)
    Grant #B-6847-S
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC) - Agreement, September 22, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 513)
  - English Language Exploratory Committee (ELEC), 1963-1967 (Box 62, Folder 514)